Some people say that dogs are man’s best friend – good companions, loyal and loveable.
有人说，狗是人类最好的朋友——它们是贴心的伙伴，忠诚又惹人喜爱。
Of course, they can be more than just a pet as certain breeds are excellent working dogs too.
当然，狗的作用远不止是宠物，有些品种还是出色的工作犬。
We know about the amazing help guide dogs give to blind people and, more recently, a new role has been found for the animals – working as therapy dogs in universities.
我们都知道导盲犬能为盲人提供极大的帮助，而近来，人们又为狗狗们找到了一个新角色——在大学里担任治疗犬。
Research by Washington State University in the US, has found spending time with a pooch can help stressed out students.
美国华盛顿州立大学的一项研究发现，和狗狗相处能帮助压力山大的学生缓解焦虑。
Patricia Pendry from the university told the BBC that a study of 300 undergraduates had found weekly hour-long sessions with dogs brought to the university by professional handlers had made stressed students at "high risk of academic failure" or dropping out, "feel relaxed and accepted".
该校的帕特里夏·彭德里向英国广播公司表示，一项针对300名本科生的研究显示，由专业驯养员带进校园的狗狗，每周和学生进行一次时长一小时的互动，可以让那些“面临高危辍学压力风险”的学生“感到放松和被接纳”。
The dogs helped them to concentrate, learn and remember information.
狗狗还能帮助他们集中注意力，更好地学习和记忆知识。
I know that stroking a dog helps me to relax; other research has shown that petting animals can reduce stress hormone levels and anxiety, so it makes sense to introduce them into an environment where people are stressed.
我知道撸狗能帮我放松；其他研究也表明，抚摸动物可以降低压力激素水平，缓解焦虑情绪。因此，把它们引入压力环境是合理的做法。
The BBC’s education correspondent Sean Coughlan writes that around 1,000 campuses in the US already use therapy pets and it’s becoming more common in the UK.
英国广播公司教育记者肖恩·考夫兰写道，美国已有约1000所大学校园配备了治疗宠物，这种做法在英国也正变得越来越普遍。
For example, The University of Middlesex has employed ‘canine teaching assistants’ to help stop lonely students dropping out.
例如，密德萨斯大学就聘请了“犬类教学助理”，帮助孤独的学生避免辍学。
Fiona Suthers, head of clinical skills at the university, says that five Labradors had a “stringent assessment” to ensure they had the right temperament.
该校临床技能负责人菲奥娜·萨瑟斯表示，五只拉布拉多犬都经过了“严格的评估”，以确保它们拥有合适的性情。
But she adds “it’s hard to describe the impact of just having a dog lying down in the corner of a class.”
但她补充道：“仅仅让一只狗趴在教室角落能产生多大的影响，这还很难说。”
Using dogs for therapy can also help the dogs themselves.
让狗狗参与治疗工作，对它们自身也有好处。
In Wales, Swansea University Students’ Union has used rescued greyhounds to help students unwind between exams.
在威尔士，斯旺西大学学生会就利用获救的灵缇犬，帮助学生在考试间隙放松身心。
Sessions allow mistreated and abandoned dogs to interact with humans and begin to trust them again.
这些互动环节能让受过虐待和被遗弃的狗狗与人类交流，重新建立对人类的信任。
Student Union education officer Chloe Hutchinson told the BBC that “a lot of students have dogs at home and might be a bit homesick, especially around exam time when it is stressful and you just want your home comforts.”
学生会教育干事克洛伊·哈钦森向英国广播公司表示：“很多学生家里都养狗，他们可能会有点想家，尤其是在考试期间，压力很大，就格外想念家里的温馨时光。”
So if you’re a student who’s been working like a dog, but you still feel like you haven’t a dog’s chance in passing your exams, maybe introducing a four-legged friend into your life might be the help you need.
所以，如果你是一名学生，已经拼命用功，却仍觉得考试及格无望，或许让一位四条腿的朋友走进你的生活，就是你需要的助力。